フルプラ
Fool on the Planet
本字幕由 SweetSub 製作　僅做交流學習之用途
翻校：ピロピラ ピロコ　其它：tastySugar
所以這見鬼的東西豎起來了
So, the damn thing stood up.
煙霧在瀰漫
It's getting pretty foggy.
太陽上升到頂空的時候就會散去的
It'll go away once the sun is at its peak.
你用不著來的
It wasn't necessary for you to come, you know.
還是說你害怕我把它扔掉？
Or were you concerned that I would throw it away?
如果它以前的力量還殘留哪怕一點點…
If this has even a fraction of the power it used to have...
別想這個了 別擔心
Just forget about it. Don't worry.
■
大豆市某處
入國管理局軌道電梯前
喂 冠軍
Hey, champ.
你還在為未來而努力訓練嗎？
Are you training hard for tomorrow?
呃 我有在努力存錢
Well, I have been trying to save my money.
很好 畢竟計劃好未來是很重要的
Good for you. It's important to make plans for the future after all.
請進
Feel free to just head on in.
往前直走就是倉庫
The warehouse is just straight ahead.
謝謝！
Thanks so much!
我的天 這個可真重
Oh man, this is heavy.
喂 你能不能小心一點？這個東西可是很貴重的！
Hey! Could you please be more careful? That thing's, like, vintage!
哎喲 對不起
Oops. My bad.
別擔心 冠軍 這就是一件破爛
No worries, champ. It's a piece of junk.
你瘋了嗎？你根本不知道—
Are you insane? Do you have any idea how much that --
我懂的 先生
I totes got it, sir.
我扔掉自己的第一部手機的時候心裡也很難受
You know, I had a hard time throwing away my first cell phone.
有時 賦予價值的是我們的感情
Sometimes sentimental value is worth the most.
你完全沒有明白！
You don't get it at all!
井出 求你了
Ah come on, Ide.
我們去遊樂場吧？
Can we please go?
我對遊樂園一點都沒有興趣
I'm not interested in amusement parks.
你為什麼不找馬可？
Why don't you ask Marco to go or something?
那傢伙今天都沒有來上學
That jackal didn't even come to school today.
他好像是有工作
I think he had to work.
他不上學去打工？
He prioritized a part-time job over school?
就你還有臉說他？兄弟 別這樣
You're one to talk. Be a sport, dude.
如果我們找一個女生一起 就只用付原票價的1%
If we take a girl, they'll give you a 99% discount.
而我可以邀請愛子 好不好？
And I can invite Aiko. So, pleeeease?
其實不是我邀請愛子的
Well, I didn't technically invite Aiko.
想去的人是她
She was the one who wanted to go.
她這麼說來著 「我想跟你一起去遊樂園
Saying stuff like, "I want to go to the amusement park with you.
但是我說不出口因為我好害羞」
I didn't want to ask 'cause it's so embarrassing."
喂 井出
Hey. Ide.
你在聽我說話嗎？
You listening to me?
諸位 聽我說
So, listen up, everybody
我有一個重要的事情要宣布
‘cause I have an important announcement to make.
我要…我要結婚了！
'Kay? Uh, I am... gonna get married!
因此我決定辭職了
And that's why I've decided to quit being a teacher.
今天是我最後一天擔任教職
Today is my last day.
從今以後 我就是一個主婦了
I'm gonna be a housewife from now on.
作為告別 我要給你們講一個故事
Since this is goodbye, let me tell you a story --
關於我和丈夫如何相愛的
how my husband and I fell in love.
所以我和老公是在大豆遊樂場相遇的
So, my hubby and I met at the Ozu amusement park.
正是夕陽西下
I was there during sunset.
笨拙的我即將被雲霄飛車碾壓
Clumsy ol' me was about to get run over by a roller coaster,
說時遲那時快 有個人救了我
when all of a sudden, someone saved me.
他就是我老公！
It was my hubby!
記住 年輕人 遊樂園就是天堂！
Remember, young ones, amusement parks are a paradise!
年輕人 丟下書本
Young people, toss your text books.
去遊樂園吧！
Let's go to the parks!
走！走！走！出發！
Go! Go! Go! Goooooo!!
雲雀弄…
Hibaji...
你怎麼了喵？好像心情不好
What's the matter, nya? You look kinda down.
女孩的煩惱喵？
Girl problems, nya?
我真正希望去遊樂園的人是你
You know, you're the one that I really wanted to go to the amusement park.
我不會去的
I'm not going.
雲雀弄！
Hibaji!
請不要糾纏她 晴子老師
Please stop bothering her, Ms. Haruko.
我們倆需要談一談
You and I need to talk.
雲雀弄 你留在這裡
Hibajiri, you stay here.
嗯？
Hm?
請你不要把酷美捲入你的計劃裡
I don't want to you involved Hidomi in your schemes.
瞧瞧你 好一位騎士
Wow, look at you. Quite the white knight, pyon.
『I think I can』—　The Pillows
好吧 打就打
Okay. Let's do this.
你真的沒有才能喵
You really got no talent, nya.
沒用的
Nope.
還是沒用
And another nope.
你應該學學怎麼用自己的球棒戰鬥
You gotta learn how to fight with your own bat.
不管你要做什麼 都要用力去做！
Whatever you want to do, you have to do it with strength!
轉動腰胯 手臂放鬆 下巴收緊
Use your hips. Arms relaxed. Keep your chin tucked in.
收緊
Tuck it in.
不行！你完全不行！
No good! You're no good at all!
你完全沒有成長
I don't see you growing.
可惜 真可惜
What a shame. What a real shame.
離酷美遠一點！
Just stay away from Hidomi!
如果人的強大是由他能承受的傷害決定
If strength was measured by the hits one could take,
那麼你就沒有那麼失敗了
then you wouldn't be considered such a loser.
實話說 我對你有過期待
To be honest, I thought you'd be better.
這就是我用了那麼多時間教育你的原因
That's why I invested all that time teaching you those things.
但是看來只是白費力氣
But I guess it was for nothing,
因為你什麼也不懂
'cause you know nothing.
晴子老師 我也很失望
I'm disappointed, too, Ms. Haruko.
你也什麼也不懂
You also know nothing.
事實上 你滿足不了我
The truth is, you don't satisfy me.
怎麼回—
What's going o--
呃 我的錯？
Uh, my bad.
最近事情好像會變得比往常更糟
Things might get worse than usual this time around.
我等著
I'll be waiting.
FLCL Progressive
情侶價只有原價的1%
99% off admission for all couples!
好便宜！
What a deal!
愛子你在哪？！
Where are you, Aiko?!
歡迎
大豆遊樂園
你不明白我的心情
You don't understand how I feel.
渡 你為什麼總是這樣？
Why are you always like this, Wataru?
美咲… - 為什麼！
Misaki... Come on!
…我喜歡你
...I love you.
我也喜歡你！
I love you, too!
裕也？
Yuya?
我… 我想…
I, uh... I would like...
我想和你一起坐旋轉茶杯！
I would like to ride the teacups with you!
裕也 你能不能不要總是出現在附近？
Yuya! Why do you keep showing up randomly?
渡 我…終於明白了自己的感情
Wataru... I... I finally realized my true feelings.
我不想知道 已經太遲了！
I don't want to hear it. You're too late.
-裕也！ -渡！
Yuya! Wataru!
不要為了我這種人爭吵 求你們了！
Please stop fighting over little old me!
■
N.O. 總量
測試運行還有多久？
Um, how much longer is this test ride?
很快就會結束了
Oh, not too much longer.
你只要乖乖待在那裡就行了
All you have to do is stay right there, okay?
■
僅限一天
青春情侶日
海盜船襲來
和渡渡鳥君聊天吧
等一下 不是這個
Wait. Hold on. Not that one.
什麼？我以為是渡渡鳥君
What? I thought it was Mr. Dodo.
別忘了 這是超高級別的機密
Don't forget, we're dealing with ultra-top-secret stuff here,
所以我們要進入機密通話模式
so we got to go into the secret-communication mode.
在購物頁面點擊幾維鳥掛墜
Push little kiwi strap at the shopping section.
蛤？哪一個？
Huh? Which one is that one?
底部中間那個毛茸茸的
The fluffy one at the bottom in the middle.
你確定嗎？打開的是個菜單
Are you sure? The link went to a menu.
接下來點「她很雞翅套餐」
You have to push She's So Chicky Wings next.
「伊卡路斯跳樓機是世界第三快的跳樓機」？
"The Icarus Fall is the world's third-fastest falling ride"?
等 等 等一下 就是那個 往回翻
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on. Right there. Go back.
-蛤？-就是那個！
Huh? That one!
就是那個 正在下落的那個
The uh... the uh... You know, the falling one.
這些好像都在下落
Uh... They're all, like, falling.
那個小鴯鶓樣子的
The one with the little emu
哪一個？
But which one?
翅膀毛茸茸的那個
The one with the fluffy wings.
具體一點！
Be more specific.
這裡！
There!
你們好！我是渡渡鳥君！
Hello there! It's Mr. Dodo!
是我
It's me.
不要擺出那副的表情 有時小孩子會誤打誤撞點進來
Don't act sorry. Sometimes a kid'll call in by mistake.
-你好 渡渡鳥君！你好 小朋友！
-Hi, Mr. Dodo! -Hey, kid!
我看到海盜船已經裝好了
I saw the Viking ship was installed.
但是還有入境方面的事情要打理
Also, we still need to deal with the Immigration matters.
我希望你不要心急
But I don't want you to have to rush.
花盆呢? 已經完成了嗎？
What about the flower plant?  Is it complete?
當然 隨時可以啟動
Sure. Uh, it can be activated any time.
真的？
Really?
已經搞定了
The plant is up, okay?
你現在還有沒有什麼情報告訴我們？
Now what intel do you have for us?
你們好！我是渡渡鳥君！
Uh, hello there!   It's Mr. Dodo!
別過來！
Ew! Get away!
你能不能專注於你真正的工作？
Can you focus on your real job?
我把數據發過去了
I sent the data.
這也是真正的工作
This is a real job, too.
你不知道利潤是用來資助—
Don't you know that this part helps fund --
沒有花盆可以嗎？
Do you think you can do it without the flower pot?
估計不行
Doubt it.
如果不能啟動花盆
If you can't activate the flower pot,
任何計劃都是白費力氣
any plan you come up with will be useless.
閉嘴 我明白
Shut up. I know that.
愛子
Aiko.
怎麼了？
What is it?
我好渴…
I'm so thirsty...
水 水…
W-water...
『Fool on the Planet』—　The Pillows
我不想回憶起今早發生的事情
I don't want to remember what happened this morning.
啊啦 快看 酷美醬！
Oh, my. Hidomi, look.
這一定是仁由小姐呢
It must be Jinyu's doing.
打碎了那麼多盤子 心裡非常在意吧
She must've felt bad about breaking so many plates.
也許吧
I guess so.
酷美醬 你變了呢
Hidomi, dear. You've changed.
我只是變回原來的自己而已
I'm back to my usual self is all.
不 不是這樣的 你真的變了
No, you're different. Completely different.
…我 變了…？
I've...changed...?
原來如此
I see...
你…你在幹什麼？
What... what are you doing?
路上小心 酷美醬
Have fun at school, Hidomi.
井出君 是你的朋友吧 他挺可愛的呢
By the way, your friend Ide? He's very cute.
為什麼…
Why are you...?
酷美醬的事情我全都知道
I know everything about you, Hidomi.
媽媽我可是酷美醬的媽媽呀
I am your mommy after all.
不是這個… -喜歡他嗎？
That's not what I... Do you like him?
我說的不是這個！
That's not what I'm talking about!
要關掉嗎？咖啡店…
You're closing it down? The cafe? Why?
為什麼？！為什麼要這樣？！
Why would you do that?
難道不是要在這裡等父親回來的嗎？！
I thought you were going to stay here and wait till Dad comes home!
我覺得也差不多了…
I think it's time to stop.
你們好！我是渡渡鳥君！
Hi! I'm Mr. Dodo!
看起來每個人都玩得很開心 對吧？
Looks like everyone is having a real good time. Am I right?
男孩們和女孩們！
Hey! Boys and girls!
你們這些下面毛都沒長齊的小屁孩！
You're little brats who still don't have all your hair down there!
很抱歉 但是你們都一無是處！
Sorry, but you are all pretty much useless!
開火！
Fire!
等一下 聲音錯了
Hold on. Wrong voice.
開火！
Fire!
他們已經開始了嗎？
They started already?
『Last Dinosaur』—　The Pillows
等等 不
Ahh! Wait! No!
隊長！情況不妙
Captain! It doesn't look like we'll make it.
我們必須這麼做
We've got to do it.
無論如何 我們向他們宣告
No matter what. We'll show them.
就算我們的褶皺被熨平
Even if our wrinkles get flattened,
我們也要戰鬥到最後一刻
we are going to fight to the very end!
開始攻擊！
Start the attack!
■
入國管理局　遺失物保管用衛星倉庫
哎呀 這是誰呀？
Oh, my. What do we have here?
多麼可愛的客人
What an adorable guest you are.
餓了嗎？
You're hungry, aren't you?
可憐的小傢伙
Oh, you poor thing.
欸？他們在做了嗎
Huh? So, they're doin' it, huh?
雲雀弄 你看起來不錯
Lookin' good, Hibaji.
你做得非常好
You're killin' it!
別急 別急呀
Wah-ho! Hold on. Hold on.
別這樣 我可什麼都沒做
Oh, come on. Stop it. I did nothing wrong.
我只是在你們這些年輕人背上輕輕推了一把
All I did was give you youngsters a little nudge,
為了幫助你們實現夢想 你知道的
to help your dreams along. You know that.
把他還給我！把井出還給我！
Give him back! Give Ide back to me!
這就是中學生的真正力量嗎？
Wah-ho! So this is the real strength of a middle-school student, huh?
到頭來 你跟其他人沒有區別
In the end, you're no different than the rest of them.
這都是因為你喜歡那隻怪鳥 對不對？
It's all because you like that weird bird, am I right?
蠢透了 你不過是一個陷入愛情的女孩
How stupid. You're just a girl in love!
是 Atomsk
It's Atomsk.